Welcome to another chat. If you go down to a beach today you might be in for a big surprise, well particularly if you're in China and it's a certain beach because you might see a completely new type of amphibious landing barge designed for invasion of Taiwan, that's pretty clear. It's unique, hasn't been seen before, quite interesting.
unscripted and it is going to be a quite a quick one today I just want to give an update on something so I've covered these barges before I was actually in a privileged position to break the story to the world a couple of months ago I wasn't the person to find them but I helped the analysis and I was able to break the story and we were right they are invasion barges but the new video and these are stills from that video stitched ever
they will be used. Because there's been an exercise in the South China Sea very near to a naval base which is used by amphibious forces which gives us a picture but I think that the beach that they were coming in on might not be that representative of the beaches that they're going to be invading in Taiwan. Let's look at it. This is that beach just Google Earth
quite pretty to be honest. Nice surf. It's a sort of beach that you'd exercise hovercraft over. It's interesting because nearby there is a base where hovercraft are stationed. Hovercraft are of course the most agile and one of the more high profile aspects of China's invasion fleet, but the new barges are a different league when it comes to unloading heavy equipment.
aircraft can carry one tank, those barges will enable a whole ferry load of tanks to be unloaded. This is how we think they're going to be used. Basically, the barge comes up to the beach, ferries unload their vehicles at the back, the vehicles then drive through the barge and across the bridge and onto dry land. Remember that Chinese ferries are
countries don't you build in a car ferry you're designing it to carry cars and trucks in China they specified they can carry tanks in Chavia going on under water we have some pilings that go down these called jack up cylinder legs that's a general term you hear of jack up barges jack up platforms the actual platform can come out of the water but they they go down and they meet the
the bottom of the sea and that gives it a really solid sort of positioning against the beach it won't get washed away quickly over time erosion will start to affect those legs but over the course of days and weeks no this is going to be really solid at the back you've got a ramp and front you got the bridge now previously we only had satellite
basically we got it right but we can learn much more now that we've also got the video previously identified there are three types in a column one two and free as I'm using Tom Shugart's naming his labels it's just like ABC we don't know the actual designations but you'll notice that type one has six of the jack up legs those orange dots and it has a loading platform at
inside the barge, much smaller jack up legs, only four of them, but also a very long bridge. And then type three is like an even larger version of type one with eight legs. I was always curious as to why type one and two and one and three versus type two, why they're so different. Type two in the middle there is quite a different design. It's not just that it's a different designer because they're built in the same shipyard.
somehow and I think we're getting the idea how because you'll notice the type one and type three have those ramp to the back whereas type two doesn't that's odd but I think it's that on the beach exercise we have a type two that's the smallest one with just four jack up legs at the front kind of if we catch if we count the legs we can work out that there's a type three and type one so they basically lined them up the smallest at the front and they get bigger as
free and the type one together like this actually makes much sense because you're not using the unloading or the loading platform at the back of the type one the one in the middle so i think that this is just a little bit for training and demonstration purposes we remember that type one doesn't have the loading platform possibly what we're
is at the front is the is the forward one against the beach and the type one is behind it or a type free for that matter i think the type ones and freeze could just unload straight onto a beach in some cases but this configuration seems to be hinted at by the differences in the design of the type two that's my update i think that these barges are potentially designed to be
to form a single pier with two or more barges we'll see i think we're going to have to watch very carefully to see how many more are built but these barges completely revolutionize the ability of china to unload large amounts of troops and equipment heavy equipment in particular to taiwan thank you for watching unscripted unedited really obvious i know please like
more flexible and more flexible and more flexible and more flexible and more flexible and more flexible and more flexible and more flexible and more flexible and more flexible and more flexible and more flexible and more flexible and more flexible and more flexible and more flexible and more flexible and more flexible and more flexible and more flexible and more flexible and more flexible and more flexible and more flexible and more flexible and more flexible and more flexible and more flexible and more flexible and more more flexible and more flexible and more flexible and more flexible and more